# Lou Caponi

# JavaScript Developer

Greater New York Area (631) 833-5798 www.loucaponi.com Idcaponi@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

Passionate and driven web application developer with a focus on the frontend. Solid experience with modern in Javascript technologies, including AngularJS, ReactJS, and Node.js. Strong skills working with teams locally and offshore. Enthusiastic about writing robust, testable, reusable code, and exploring the evolving JS landscape.

#### **SKILLS**

Javascript (ES6), ReactJS, Redux, Vue, AngularJS, Node.js, Git, MongoDB

# **EXPERIENCE**

CA Technologies, Islandia, NY - Senior Applications Developer

August 2017 - PRESENT

- Oversee a team of developers building multiple applications using React and Redux.
- Build CI/CD pipelines and deployment environments using Microsoft Azure products.

Raymond James Financial via FDM Group, St. Petersburg, FL - UI Developer

June 2015 - July 2017

- Developed flexible, reusable components for a dashboard application using AngularJS.
- Managed development of multiple features simultaneously using the Gitflow workflow.
- Increased collaboration and code quality by performing normal code reviews.
- Met business deliveries by communicating with backend teams, business analysts, and QA team.

FDM Group, New York, NY- Consultant in Training - Java Development

March 2015 - June 2015

- Completed 4 month training program, focusing on developing full-stack enterprise Java applications.
- Gained development skills ranging from backend development (Java, SQL, JDBC, Hibernate), to frontend (JSP's, Javascript).
- Learned industry standard best practices, including TDD (JUnit), design patterns (Factory, Observer, Singleton), single responsibility, and code encapsulation.

# **EDUCATION**

University of South Florida, Tampa, FL- M.A. in Pure and Applied Mathematics

August 2011 - May 2014

Southeastern University, Lakeland, FL- B.A. in Mathematics

August 2008 - May 2011

# **INTERESTS**

Love to surf and snowboard, and get in the gym to destress. Like to explore local restaurants with friends. Try to get out of the country once or twice a year to keep things interesting.